Heavy metal goes medieval.
Ironclad is a romance, adventure, action film directed by Jonathan English.
In the year 1215, the rebel barons of England have forced their despised King John to put his
royal seal on the Magna Carta, a seminal document that upheld the rights of free men.
Yet within months of pledging himself to the great charter, the King reneged on his word and assembled a mercenary army on the
south coast of England with the intention of bringing the barons and the country back under his tyrannical rule.
Barring his way stood the mighty Rochester castle, a place that would become the
symbol of the rebel's momentous struggle for justice and freedom.
Thomas Marshall, played by James Purefoy.
Lady Isabel, played by Kate Mara.
Becket, played by Jason Flemyng.
King John, played by Paul Giamatti.
Albany, played by Brian Cox.
Cornhill, played by Derek Jacobi.
Ironclad is a 2011 British action historical drama
film directed by Jonathan English.
Written by English and Erick Kastel, based on a screenplay by Stephen McDool, the cast includes James Purefoy, Brian Cox,
Kate Mara, Paul Giamatti, Vladimir Kulich, Mackenzie Crook, Jason Flemyng, Derek Jacobi, and Charles Dance.
The film chronicles the siege of Rochester Castle by King John in 1215.
The film was shot entirely in Wales in 2009 and
produced on a budget of $25 million.
The film explores themes of hero, ambush, fight, castle, battlefield.
The tone is emotional.